LEIGHA ROBINSON

SOFTWARE DEVEOPER

CONTACT

1-613-981-1366

Lmarobinson24@gmail.com

https://leigharobinson.github.io/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/leigha-robinson/

https://github.com/leigharobinson

ABOUT ME

After my ice hockey career ended, I took all the passion I had training to achieve an elite level in my sport and poured that energy into exploring my other interests. While attending the University of Tennessee at Knoxville, I took an introduction into computer programming class that opened my eyes to the power of programming.

While completing my music degree in Canada, I still would help friends and family with website design. I knew when I moved back home to Nashville I wanted to make the career change into tech and continue my programming education. NSS has been an invaluable tool in expediting my journey into the tech industry.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Semantic UI
- React, jQuery, Reactstrap
- · Python, Django, SQL
- Git/GitHub, JSON
- FIGMA, GIMP

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School 4/20 - Present

Full Stack Software Developer

Carleton University 2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Arts; Music

University of Tennessee, Knoxville 2009 - 2012

Biochemistry

HONORS & AWARDS

- Senate Medal recipient for Outstanding Academic Achievement - 2018
- 1st Girl Selected for ALL STARS Brentwood High School 2007-2008 Ice Hockey Season

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School | 4/20 - Present

NSS is an intensive software development bootcamp that focuses learning in both individual and team-based projects

- Tech stacks HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Python/Django and SQL fundamentals
- Git/Github, the fundamentals are important for version control and division of labor within a programming team
- Confidence working remotely. Due to COVID classes used ZOOM for lessons and group projects.

PROJECTS

Join Their Journey With Music

https://github.com/leigharobinson/dementia_music_memory https://github.com/leigharobinson/jointheirjourney-withmusic

Connects caregivers with a valuable tool for making musical selections that impact those living with dementia. Capability to record and store patient responses to musical selections in order to build data of what songs might be best used to distract, comfort and give autonomy to dementia patients.

- Javascript to handle condition logic
- React to handle user input and create DOM
- FIGMA, React-Bootstrap for styling
- Full Stack application with CRUD capabilities.
- Constructed Diango REST API to handle data
- Python to handle conditional logic in backend

Forget Me Not

https://github.com/leigharobinson/ForgetMeNot

Allows users to build a virtual wallet that can quickly sort Gift Cards, Coupons and Rewards and track important information such as expiration dates

- Javascript to handle condition logic
- React to handle user input and create DOM
- FIGMA, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, and Reactstrap for styling
- Full CRUD capabilities.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Children's Choir Director/Section Lead

Rideau Park United Church Ottawa, ON | 2015 - 2018

- Organized concerts, classes, events. Taught team-building skills to students
- Taught music rudiments: rhythm, melody, basic sight reading, vocal ability

Auditor of Ottawa West Newspaper Region

Metroland Media Group Ottawa, ON 2015 - 2017

- Gathered data to create reports used by the sales team to gain new advertising clients
- Utilized new GPS locating technologies and other company software (comparable to Excel) and applied them to created detailed reports on Newspaper circulation